The Institution
Tell me, Herr von Wagner
You said we were just having a normal football evening
We are,
but we wanted to look at the problems in our host country, you know?
A kind of critical barbeque
The state of the sausages really is critical
Do you understand, critical?
We are FIFA
Ah, the Freetime Institute for Foolish Agitators
What?
No, we are For Investigative Football Appreciation
You see?
Not just seeing football, but seeing through it
A typical Wagner trick
What's the limbo rod there for?
It symbolises, of course, the contortions Brazil is doing just to host this event
What's that tulip picker doing here?
He symbolises the beauty
of football
And someone's got to lose
In Holland, we showed Geert Wilders the art of losing
You taught the AfD ["Neonazi" party] how to win
Sorry, but why is she there?
For the stadium atmosphere, or what?
Wait a minute, Uthoff
World Cup 2003, European Cup 2005
World Cup 2007, European Cup 2009 and 2013
Those are all uneven numbers
There weren't any world cups
I'm talking about women's football
You know, maybe it's easier to win without
a second striker
Uthoff
You definitely drew the short straw there
Come, let's watch the pre-match commentary
No!
Yes!
Then at least then we'll see the Dutch players a bit
No, we can't watch football yet
We haven't been critical
Football and critical thinking don't go together anyway
Of course they do
You see,
The fundamental idea of football is freedom
Who says that?
Uli Hoeneß? [football player and tax evader]
Cesar Luis Benotti
Argentinian coach, '74-'83
That's it
He wasn't just a football trainer, but a critical spirit
Because he was a chain smoker?
No, after the world cup of '78,
he refused to shake the dictator's hand
Because he had a cigarette in his hand?
No, out of political consciousness
Argentina '78?
Couldn't find any critical football thinkers in 2014?
Of course, there are many critical footballers
There's...
V... Völler!
He almost hit a Dutchman once
Hey, Conchita, throw us a sausage
Herr Uthoff...
Sausage jokes have a beard this long
Here, your critical sausage
Yes, I can see that
but where is the meat?
It's vegan
So you're a Turkey sympathiser?
Come on, let's start
We will start with a documentary about the seamstress at Adidas
Not that!
Have they even qualified?
We want to watch football!
How can you watch football
if you don't even know what it costs?
But it's on free TV!
We still have to bet!
Oh yes!
I bet if you examine the details of this world cup for half an hour
you won't want to watch it
I'll bet on that
If I lose interest in football,
I'll wear your limbo hat
And if I win, I'll take my jersey off
And I'll help you
What?
If I lose,
I'll walk through Amsterdam in your jersey
Excellent
Then let's start with the strongest argument there is:
FIFA
I love the smell of napalm on Tuesday evening
I told you the state of the sausages was critical
Good day
Hi
I'm your FIFA partner
Here's my card
"Last night was nice,
call me, Yvonne."
"Treter:
Football executioner"
Football executive
This is my partner
The world cup mascot
He's an armadillo
Yellow, blue
and endangered
Like the FDP Party
Tell me,
what's he called?
A mixture of football and ecological
It symbolises the esteem we have for our host country
Wait a minute, fuleco is Brazillian
for "arse"
Correct
And what are you doing here?
Well, what does it look like
Well
Billows of smoke,
a Dutchman,
and two overzealous lefties
trying to impress the village beauty
Is this about canabis legalisation?
No!
Listen, we're having a critical barbeque
So, a political event?
Yes sir!
We want to use football's popularity for social change
You know, in the tradition of Minotti and...
Völler
Exactly
FIFA la revolution
That banner overhead,
that has to go
Why?
FIFA and overheads?
That doesn't go together
And what does it even mean?
Oh, that's the slogan of the Brazilians opposing this world cup
It means, "There will be no world cup"
Then the screen will stay blank
Al Capone said
I mean, Joseph Blatter said
we need to protect our sport from political influence
Then Merkel's not allowed in the stands?
No, you can't protest here anymore
What?
You have to decide
Either football
or this Christian barbeque
OK, then no question
Then no football for a few weeks, right, men?
No...  But we want...
Now look what I have here
You can have fun without watching football!
But we can be critical at half time...
Stop!
Where is your solidarity for the people of Brazil?
Brazil is getting something out of it!
Modern streets are being built
People are pouring into the...
slums
Look, they've spent €3 billion on stadiums
Those were all private investments
That's what they told the people
And now the state has paid everything
And the private investors
0 cent
That's it
And they don't need stadiums,
they need hospitals and schools
Fat Renaldo said
you can't play football in hospitals
And he's an expert
Listen to me
They're building enormous stadiums,
some for 3rd-league clubs
You don't build an Allianz Arena for Wacker Burghausen!
Why not?
I'll spur them on to get out of this misery
Great, useless stadiums for VIPS
and the people are sitting in the shit
Herr von Wagner,
you're becoming vulgar
Half of all Brazillian households
don't have running water
Holy shit
Precisely
170,000 people were forced to relocate
They had to leave their homes forever
so we can watch two weeks of football
And what's FIFA doing?
Making money
€4 billion profit
Do you want to watch football or not?
No!
How awful
We're becoming champions and I can't see it
But the stadiums were already there
Otherwise those people would have died for n...
Herr von Wagner
I really do always have an ear for the underprivileged
But I need a break every 4 years
You know what?
That
is not why we occupied this Institution
You see, you only get emotions like these with football
You won't regret it
After the first kick,
all your problems will be forgotten
Maybe Herr von Wagner is right
Football and politics can go together
It only depends
who you kick
Look at this, for example
The Turkish vice head of state, Yakel,
with a beautiful drop kick against a protester
His team manager, Erdogan, took him straight out of the lineup
because he hadn't understood the most important criterea for joining the EU:
"Don't kick
Have other people do it for you"
Europe
Europe has voted, and the result is not surprising
When you spend years ignoring large differences in income
Years holding onto an brutal austerity policy
It's no wonder
when the lower-income
and now even higher-income bracket in Northern Europe
fall into the hands of hand-picked scum
like Orbán and LePenn
The British don't want to play anymore, maybe
But who wants the British
Yes, they do have a good sense of humour
They need it, with their looks
The choice
The choice between Martin Schulz and Jean-Claude Schulz
electrified the people
like licking an old 1.5V battery
Just before the election, Martin Schulz told people to vote
to drown out the voice of the right-wing populists
And at the same time,
has his postcard face printed on billboards
garnished with the slogan:
"From Germany, for Europe"
Then, at the latest, you understand why casting a vote
always sounds a bit like having no voice
The provincial character of this election
can bee seen particularly clearly in this picture:
[Asparagus]
But at least everyone elligible to vote obeyed the golden rule of every election:
"One man - one vote"
Everyone
except
Giovanni di Lorenzo
The chief editor of the weekly paper Die Zeit
admitted before millions of viewers
that he voted twice
Once in the Italian consulate
and once in a primary school in Hamburg
Although we all know,
if only from Monty Python's "The Life of Brian",
only one cross each
Enough about the shortage of skilled workers
The public prossecution department is investigating election fraud
Ukraine voted too
The changing of the oligarch
Now we have one dipped in chocolate
Taste: bittersweet
The new oligarch has already stated
his plans to visit the regions in crisis in the east
And yesterday, to be on the safe side,
he sent the military ahead of him
The process of reconciliation has begun
Score at half time:
More than 50 dead
But the road has to be cleared
for western investors
The American VP's son, Hunter Biden,
is already indentured
in the board of the Ukranian gas and energy corporation Burisma
And if you say,
"But you can't do that
Dealing out the silver before the body's cold"
They'll tell you:
I'm curious if Frank Walter Steinmeier
will maybe get angry about this as well
Listen to me,
I'm in the middle of my solo!
Herr Uthoff
You may have forgotten
ZDF is a FIFA partner
You're obliged
to give the mascot screen time at any moment
You know, I've heard that armadillos
are endangered
He's getting so worked up
People in our profession are expected to get worked up
But privately I've given it up
"Laid-back" is the new catchword
If we can learn one thing from our chancellor,
it's how to be laid-back
Pity she won't share her potato soup recipe
But everything is great
Crises?
Ah, that'll pass
There are things you can hold on to
Thing which always stay the same
Lothar Mattäus has just got a kid
on that Russian bimbo
Something like that stabilises you
Maybe one day Schröder will adopt her
out of solidarity with Russia
Laid-back
It's also true of Burger King
I bet they'll soon have a massive turnover
Heidi Klum just needs to say
that she can lose 15 kilos quickly and easily
with foodpoisoning
"My burger's not stale, it's slim-fast!"
Everything is wonderful
Yes, look!
There are just a few catches
like retirement at 63 or 93
But let's be honest
With the state of our retirement homes
Everyone works there voluntarily anyway
until they kick the bucket
And if you don't want to anymore,
with 60 a Rex Gildo, 6th floor, and basta
We're heading towards a great time
Look, after a few years of war in the Ukraine
we'll have prime conditions for an economic miracle in Eastern Europe
In Germany it'll rain money
Greece will reopen the euro rescue parachute
And Erdogan will be driven out by his own people
And together with Silvio Berlusconi, in a Roman retirement home,
will read his biography aloud
to retired strippers
"Inshallah: Between baton and Koran"
Sepp Blatter, after one look from Sahra Wagenknecht,
cools football stadiums in Qatar down to -16 degrees
Tebartz van Elst [Catholic priest]
has to give up his swanky home
and move in with his children
And Annette Schavan
Annette Schavan holds up the Vatacan
and ends 1000-year-old dogmas
to make one thing possible:
the canonisation of our living European dictator,
Angela Merkel
And Saint Angela pilgrims devoutly
to Frankfurt, to the German banking centre
and kneels at the grave
of the unknown banker
I can't wait
Do you have your cards?
Yeah, let's trade!
I have an album
Can I see?
OK
I have Don Julio Grondona
What curruption score does he have?
7/10 on the Blatter scale
He's very good at money laundering, tax evasion and...
It says corruption
€70 million in slush funds
Not bad!
And what's his statement score?
9/10
What did he say?  Give here
"I don't think that a Jewish referee can be on the same level
Because it's hard work, and we know
Jews don't like hard work"
Um, is that bad?
He got the FIFA Order of Merit
It can't be that bad
I also have a right-winger
Arjen Robben
But he didn't even get a yellow card last season!
I have Jack Warner
Where did he play?
He was in the FIFA...
executive committee
And he has a way high curruption score, look!
He built a training centre for €25 million
That's not even illegal!
It is on your private property
Also...
He tried to buy votes in the FIFA presidential election
But everyone does that
Yeah
But not votes against Sepp Blatter
He also got himself caught
Look who I have
Jérôme Valcke!
Is he still playing?
Of course, stupid
He's the second most important, after Blatter
They once did some really naughty stuff
FIFA had to pay a €90m fine
Because he cheated
a FIFA sponsor, Mastercard
with Visa
With Lisa?
But my dad said they fired him
They did
And rehired him after 6 months
As a caretaker?
No, as secretary general
A man secretary!
I have two of this one
José Maria Marin
He has an awesome dictatorship score
Robben, too
Rubbish
Has too, he played for 4 years under Mourinho
Look, that's nothing compared to Marin
He has insanely...
Look!
The blood of a dictatorship is on his hands
And it's allegedly his fault that a journalist was turtured and murdered
And what's he going now?
He's preparing for the world cup in Brazil
He'll be at the opening
Next to the president, Dilma Rousseff
Do they love each other?
I dunno...
But I don't think so
Because Rousseff once had a husband
and he was tortured in that dictatorship
And Marin approved of it
And then she has to sit next to him at the opening?
Yeah
But FIFA alway says,
"Football brings people together"
Guess who I have here?
Carlos Alberto Lacoste
What's so great about him?
Listen, he organised the world cup in Argentina, during the military dictatorship
And Argentina desperately wanted to win
Then they said to Peru,
"If you win,
we'll give you heaps of money
and torture your political enemies"
Evil
And then?
Then, Peru lost and Argentina became world champions
Against Holland
That's mean!
Did they at least throw him in a dirty hole?
You could say that
He became FIFA vice president
Although he'd been a dictator
In a dictatorship where 30,000 people died
- Evil!
- Yeah, evil
If Blatter knew...
Yeah...
Hello, children
Uncle Blatter knows everything
He recently said, about this matter in Argentina,
"I was happy that Argentina won
Between the population and the political system,
there was a kind of reconciliation"
Evil...
Children?
I have something for you here
Joseph Blatter!
He doesn't look very nice
Yeah, my mum said he has a yucky infection
Can I have him?
No, no one can get him
You only get him when you've bought all the others
Hey Uncle do you have pictures of the builders?
Who died on the construction sites in Qatar?
But they don't have any faces
Hey Uncle, what class are you in?
I'm a FIFA official
And you?
Aren't you afraid of me?
No
I've got Snowden
It's funny
No one wants to keep him
But the guy's a hero
When he started to consider exposing the NSA
he was in his late 20s
He was getting a 6-digit salary from the NSA, I think
Was living in Hawaii with his girlfriend
And she was, I quote,
"A good-looking dancer"
A good-looking dancer!  In Hawaii!
For that life,
I would not only have sold my grandmother to the NSA,
but left her bound and gagged outside their headquarters
And what did Snowden do?
He sacrificed this freedom
to warn us of the threat to ours
And what have we done with this sacrifice?
We got Pofalla onto it
He was the one who whiped the affair from the table
OK, when they tapped the Chancellor's phone,
he reacted at once
Set the Facebook relationship status with America
to "it's complicated"
Then the Chancellor intervened, said "That's not OK!"
And she called in the American embassy
That was the harshest diplomatic action available to us
One hour, alone
with Guido Westerwelle [minister of foreign affairs]
When that proved fruitless,
the politicians went en masse to Washington,
hopping mad
Recently De Maizière again
De Maizière went hopping mad to Washington,
came back with the realisation,
"Snowden is a criminal"
And now we're supposed to have a "cyber dialogue" with the USA
A cyber dialogue!
What is that?
The NSA is now going to call us back?
Nonetheless
Nonetheless, we now have an NSA investigation committee
And our government is doing everything in its power
to obstruct their work
And that's why they've now decided
to question Snowden
Only they forgot to clarify
where
and how, and what, and why
out of fear that Obama will get angry
That's
manifold violations of fundamental rights
What are those
compared to the raised eyebrows of an American president?
That's anchored in our constitution:
"A person's dignity is inviolable
Details are regulated by an American law"
When
Thank you very much
If the government really refuses to get Snowden over here,
to really question him properly,
out of fear that the NSA wouldn't work with us anymore,
this country is saying very clearly
The work of spies is more important to us
than the constitution
But I can understand that
Spies are sexy
The constitution is 65
And maybe the government isn't that afraid of the Americans
Maybe they're more afraid of Edward Snowden
and his remarks about
the unconstitutional conduct
of the BND [German intelligence]
Maybe that would raise more questions
than the government is prepared to answer
It's quite funny that no one knows how to treat Snowden
The University of Rostock wanted to award him an honorary doctorate, for example
And then the head of the university jumped in at the last minute
"That's not allowed
You can only get an award like that for scientific achievements"
And giving information to the media is not a scientific achievement
Do you know who got his honorary doctorate in Rostock?
Joachim Gauk [German president]
1999, do you know why?
For reworking databases
Yeah, Stasi documents
But you can't compare Snowden with Gauk
The University of Rostock would like their students to take this away:
"Become whistleblowers
but only when the regime you're denouncing
has already collapsed"
You can't trust anyone anymore, huh?
I can't be arsed
Always this bad news
from people in a bad mood,
in badly-fitting suits
I wish Klaus Kleber would say for once,
"Good evening and welcome to today's Journal
Nothing today, not even weather, good night"
I don't even know what's good and bad anymore
That was so easy before
Before, you knew
"American good
Russian bad"
"Nutella good,
Nusspli bad"
Nowadays it's not that simple
Barack Obama has a Nobel Peace Prize
and a trusted person
A trusted person who's spying on half the world
Who was given the Nobel Peace Prize
and is still running Guantanamo Bay on the side
2009, as he was inaugurated,
he said he'd close the thing within one year
The thing's still open
The only thing he did close
was the office responsible for resolving Guantanamo Bay
And in this wave of enthusiasm,
he was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize
when he had just 3 days earlier
sent 30,000 men and women to fight in Afghanistan
He shouldn't have got a peace prize for that
but an Oscar
Awarding Barack Obama the Nobel Peace Prize
is like restropectively presenting the terrorists of 9/11
with a prize for town planning
It's not that far-fetched
Mohammed Atta, one of the terrorists,
had studied town planning in Hamburg
Back then he said,
"I'll do something later with large buildings"
Who can I trust anymore?
Look at the ADAC [automobile association], that's a respectable joint
Now I know the Hells' Angels are more transparent
They falsified votes and voter participation so drastically
Kim Jong-un's ears would have gone red
On the other hand, now I know why they're called the "Yellow Angels"
They always pissed themselves laughing at their member's gullibility
Who can I trust?
OK, the Catholic church
They've been doing everything right for centuries
So the management up there is alright
The problem is the people on the ground
Cardinal Meisner ended his career with the words:
"One of your families is worth three Muslim families"
It's this integrative thought
that makes you wonder if they weren't smoking their insense
That poses the big question
Are they suffering from dementure
or rabies?
Who can I trust?
Look
I always used to trust advertising
Where they always said "Cats would buy Whiskers"
I stood in the supermarket for weeks
Not one cat came
And now I've learnt why
The cats on minimum wage
can't even afford Whiskers
On that note, welcome to today's Journal,
nothing today, not even weather
Herr Simon
I have to apologise to you
I will never make another dumb Dutchman joke
Would be nice, but why?
Because you're so courageous
Here I have this FIFA contract
which every land has to sign before it can host a world cup
And Holland was the only country brave enough to publish this contract
Yes
Although, with your world cup tally
What did you have to lose?
Our conscience
You don't know it, it can't be bought
Do you still stand by your bet?
Yes
No
Yes, but look
This contract, from the FIFA
It's a contract for pure oppression
It places you outside of the host country's employment code
It's a license to exploit
Look here, in paragraph three:
They don't pay taxes
So FIFA doesn't pay any taxes
from the announcement of the host to the end of the world cup
The construction companies, the franchisees,
FIFA's trade partners, none of them pay tax
Neither do the sponsors
Companies worth millions invade a country,
dig out all the money,
and foist off the costs on the taxpayers
If you say yes one more time, do you know what I'll do with you?
No
But please explain, how can it be
that entire countries spread their legs when FIFA comes?
It's a non-profit organisation
with €1.4 billion reserves
And the officers are swimming in money
How the hell do they manage that?
That's very easy, FIFA has a product that everyone wants
but only they supply
Making money out of that is like shooting into an unguarded goalpost
Wait a minute
They have to sell the TV rights
And there must be some kind competition for that, right?
FIFA can't shut that out so easily
They can, for years they've sold the rights to the same intermediary
To the highest bidder
No, to the lowest
What kind of stragegy is that?
Because the one who bid the lowest
offered the officials the most
Over the years about €140m
- And that works?
- Yes
Like clockwork
I'd say that's a case for the courts
It's not like we're in a banana republic
Even worse: we're in Switzerland
What's that supposed to mean?
FIFA headquarters are in Switzerland
where until recently corruption by private persons
was not punishable
Private persons?  It's a billion-dollar business
It's a society
like pidgeon breeders
Only that they're breeding mice
Yes, and taxfree
I've had enough
I'm going to the police
Look, Interpol
Specialists in fighting corruption, they'll...
What are you doing?
That's the police!
And I'm FIFA and I've just donated €20m
FIFA donates €20m to Interpol?
Why?
That's pure corruption
That's fighting corruption
What?
Wait, FIFA gives the police money to fight corruption?
Not against FIFA
They should fight corruption in the Middle East or something
Preventative, or something like that
Gentlemen
I'm picking up a sense of distrust towards FIFA
I have a proposition for you
We'll get ourselves a neutral referee
Under one condition:
He can't look into our past
Otherwise something would come to light
Allow me to introduce to you
the investigator of our ethical commission, state prossecutor Michael Garcia
Wait a minute
He sounds familiar
He was in charge when the Leman Brothers' Bank collapsed
It was the worst supervision failure in the history of the American economy
Exactly our requirements
Expensive and incompetent
Don't you follow any rules?
We are the rules
Go play with yourself
We, the FIFA, prefer to play with ourselves
We establish our own laws
without waiting for foreign courts to show us the way
Sometimes you need to stay off-field
Now everyone's saying
we imposed enormous costs on the Brazilians for new stadiums
and I say
it's their own fault
There are other solutions
The next world cup is in Russia
And look at Vladimir Putin
He's already started annexing neighbouring countries
so he has enough stadiums by 2018
And of course there weren't any problems with demonstrations
I'm not worried about that
These female activists are the only ones who are protesting in Russa anyway
And female protestors
That's like women's football
Young, pretty creatures
floundering in a discipline
their bodies aren't designed for
"Pussy Riot"
That's what we call our shareholders' meeting after-party
"Pussy Riot" - what kind of outrageous name is that?
[literal German translation]
I once googled "pussy riot"
I got Frank Walter Steinmeier's Youtube clip
Putin won't let Alfons Hörmann ruin his beautiful world cup
When, after all those preparations,
he can finally stand proudly on the VIP stand
at the opening match in Warsaw
On his left side, his new life partner,
Gerhard,
the Carla Bruni of managed democracy
And on his right, my boss,
His Royal Delinquency, Joseph the First
Imagine this triarchy:
Schröder, Putin, Blatter
The id, the ego and the superego
They should invite Uli Hoeneß too, maybe
He'll be out of jail by then
And it'll put the critics in a more forgiving mood
and they can tell themselves, "Well
at least one of them has been in prison."
Uli Hoeneß is good at this PR thing
I said it from the start, denuncing himself
was a marketting strategy
He'd like to touch up his club's image
The Bavarians are always seen as bigwigs
They have the most money, the best players, the biggest wins
But also the sex appeal of Uschi Glas [German film and television actress]
Come on, she's sexy
It's a club like Sankt Pauli or 1816 Münchhen
They have a mongrel-like quality
which reminds you football is played below the belt
And that's why Hoeneß thought he'd get his club a bit of street cred
"Warrent of arrest" has the scent of the streets
Soon everyone will say "The Bavarians,
those are ghetto kickers"
The former president is an ex-con
And the sport director's an East German skinhead
He's a real ganster, Hoeneß, right?
In the space of just 4 days at court,
his tax due went from €3.5m
to €28.5m
Those are skyrocketing costs
So if he gets out of the slammer and the Bavarians don't want him back after all
he could still get a place on the parish council in Limburg
Ladies and gentlemen, my dear football fans,
Third World vs. First League:
The seamstresses from El Salvador are playing today
against their nemesis,
an Adidas shareholder
We're hoping for an exciting match
It's already so late
I sew 11 hours a day in the factory, but
Financially I'm making no mark
You can't imagine
How bad my day was
I'll say this much: shareholders' meeting
The whole time, feeding on the little guys
I've really put on weight, I think
That was the last bowl of rice
Well, I guess tomorrow we'll start
A rice diet!
That's what we'll have to do sometime
2 or 3 kilos
Rice
We could live off that for one or two weeks
But with the €160 I earn each month
You can't really get ahead, you know?
Recently, in the first quarter, Adidas only made €200m surplus
You know what the worst part is?
Wolf
€80m just because this stupid golf division isn't working in America
Out profits went up €800m nonetheless
We raised dividends
The shareholders should be happy, but
the seamstresses are being squeezed out like lemons
Always more, what more are we supposed to do?
Beating seamstresses
Yes, there are forewomen who beat seamstresses
When they don't manage to make enough items
You heard right, we were really beaten
by Nike
€2.5 billion
And we?
Can't even afford to eat properly from our wages
We have one last hope
A union
But we're not allowed to start one
Yeah
We'll always slip further and further
behind Nike
Brazil is our last chance
We have to get €2 billion our of the world cup, otherwise
We don't stand a chance
If you just say the world "union" you're on the black list
That's why we keep on doing forced overtime, even on holidays
There are mothers who often don't see their children for weeks
That's really...
Awesome
You know?
Because these national team jerseys sell like
Urinary tract infections
Yes
They raised our targets
300 jerseys a day
You only manage that without toilet breaks
And you only manage that by not drinking the whole day
Hence the infections
Yes, we really need a push
For the world cup, we're making one of the biggest campaigns in advertising history
One of my colleagues is now making a lecture tour in Germany
Maybe people there will notice
Oh yes, we were really dishing out money
Last year alone €1.5 billion for marketting
I would actually need three times as much as my current salary
to feed my family properly
But next year, we want to make a surplus of €1 billion
That would be good
It's working quite well with that world cup ball
People like that... What's it called again?
Estella Ramirez, is my friend's name
She's been fighting for years for better conditions for women in the factories
But you know what Adidas says to that?
Brazuca!  That's it!
Brazuca is that name of this Adidas world cup ball
Adidas has even written on its homepage,
"Well, when the wages are raised,
we shift our production to places
where wages are lower"
"Brazuca", you know what that means?
Warm-heartedness
Ladies and gentlemen, a high quality match, I thought
Fought with emotion
Let's hear what our FIFA official has to say about it
Herr Treter?
My apologies
That was nothing, Herr Uthoff
A couple of overpaid satirists
Collecting "concerned points" at the expense of fictional workers
Then your concern was fake?
Of course, but the fate behind it is real
That could be entirely possible
I'm told we have Estella Ramirez on the line
The connection is running
Dear viewers of the Establishment
I am Estella Ramirez from El Salvador
My colleagues and I
sew together your Adidas jerseys
The work...
I'm back
We were just experiencing problems with the connection, where were we?
With Estella Ramirez, a seamstress who spoke in Germany recently at the Adidas shareholders' meeting
How did that go?
Great
3 out of the 4 biggest shareholders left the room
I've had enough of Adidas
What do these shitty jerseys cost?
€79.95, and what do the seamstresses earn?
80c goes towards wages
1%
99% goes to the people who sell the jerseys,
who talk about them, or have their photo taken in them
Now I know what this absurd slogan means
Yeah, Adidas is raking it all in
Not entirely
According to media calculations, Adidas pays the most expensive player
€300,000 to wear their jersey
monthly
So to Adidas, a football player
is worth 2000 times more than a seamstress
Well, a football player like that is supposed to entertain millions of people
A seamstress can't even support her family
I've had enough
I don't want to watch this world cup anymore
Me neither
Out jerseys are pinned together in Bangladesh
They wouldn't have won anyway
What are you doing, Frau Gruber?
Taking my jersey off
Wagner, you've won your stupid bet
And I'll gladly help you
Have fun with it in Amsterdam
Hold on, what's that?
I am now
a FIFA
A Female In Fair Apparel
Oh God
Yes, I want...
I want fair play
off the field, too
And not just at Adidas
but at Puma, Nike
We need to put pressure on the manufacturers
We're shooting down FIFA
with a critical goal wall shooting
Shoot away
As long as you watch football, we have the power
I'm done with that, I'm not watching
So, Herr von Wagner, I have to admit
You've won your stupid bet
Tell me, a football evening with no football is... What are we going to do now?
Come on, there's four of us
We have balls and even our own goal post
Come on, we're making our own world cup!
We're taking back football!
And we're throwing that out the window
Team revolution!
And because it's a fair world cup
the team wins who needs it the most!
That was the Establishment
Occupied today by...